MESIOYE SAMSON

Address: 5, Tunde Abimbola Street, Magodo phase II, Magodo-Lagos.

Email: jazzygee36@gmail.com Phone: 08181256788

Professional Summary

Self-motivated Web and App Developer with 2 years of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with a penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in roles indulging best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

<u>Skills</u>

- HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap4, SASS, Chakra ui, Material ui
- JavaScript, TypeScript
- React JS, Next JS
- Node JS, Express
- MongoDB
- Git, Github
- Api testing(Postman, REST Client)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Mid React JS Developer

Plagad

Nov 2021 – Current Ikeja, Lagos.

Responsibilities:

- Designed the Front-end applications as well for user interactive (UI) web pages using web technologies like HTML5, Chakra, JavaScript, React JS and TypeScript.
- Worked as a Front End Developer on the project with JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML5/Chakra and Github.
- Involved in designing in web pages using HTML 5, XHTML, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js, useContext, React-Bootstrap, Node.js, express.js, Mongo DB.
- Wrote well designed, testable, efficient code with HTML, Chakra, JavaScript, TypeScript and React JS.

- Constructing and testing end user applications to meet user needs using Chakra as Designed System.
- Achieved APIs calls from back end NodeJS using React axios.
- Designed layouts on the front-end and developed web pages responsive for smart phones, tablets and Personal desktops using HTML5, Chakra ui and React JS.

Junior React JS Developer

Jan 2021- Oct 2021

MIN Lekki, Lagos.

Responsibilities:

- Worked as Front-end Software Engineer
- Develop high performance customer facing E-commerce using JavaScript, React JS, Next JS and Materia ui as the Designed System.
- Used NextJs for server-side rendering for better performance and for SEO.
- Implementing functionalities at the Front-end level using state and useContext.
- Skilled in leading frameworks as React.js to build high-quality, scalable and reusable components and Front-end solution.
- Designed layouts on the front-end and developed web pages responsive for smart phones, tablets and Personal desktops using HTML5, Material UI, React JS.
- Achieved APIs calls from back end NodeJS using React axios.
- Developed an internal application using React JS, Next JS, Express and Node JS for Relationship Mangers.

Junior JavaScript Developer

Apr 2020- Oct 2020

Bedge

Lekki phase II, Lagos.

Responsibilities:

• Creating an interface that is user friendly using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

• Documented code, so other developers can understand and contribute to it

Worked in designing, developing and testing the web application by using the HTML5,

CSS3, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.

• Worked in designing the CSS templates for use in all pages on the website working with

CSS Background, positioning, text, border, margin, padding, and table.

• Designed layouts on the front-end and developed web pages responsive for smart

phones, tablets and Personal desktops using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery,

• Developed Graphics using Paint Shop, Corel draw and Photoshop.

• Worked alongside with a senior developer.

EDUCATION:

❖ Yaba College of Education(YabaTech)

Course: Computer Science

Peter king College of Music

Instrument Major: Saxopone

2020 - Yaba, Lagos

2013 - Oko-Afon, Lagos